<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: learning | Nacho Lopez]]></title>
  <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/categories/learning/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T16:46:42+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nacho Lopez]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nacho@nlopez.io]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shipping as fast as possible]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/03/30/shipping-as-fast-as-possible/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T22:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/03/30/shipping-as-fast-as-possible</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m taking
<strong>a different approach</strong>
 with my newest app,
<strong>BikeShare! for iOS</strong>
.</p>

<p>I always wanted to have a lot of functionality done before I could even think about shipping, but it seems a really bad idea now. Sure, the app would be awesome when done… but
<strong>when would that be</strong>
? I have very little free time and a lot of projects going on, shifting my focus from time to time due priority changes or even boredom whims, so it’s hard to know about times.</p>

<p>So I changed my mind. I decided on a basic core functionality and went with it. The 1.0 version will have that and nothing more.</p>

<p>Then I will have some valuable info I might need to know before adding more functionality. With the core done and some stats mining frameworks set up, like
<a href="http://www.mymalcom.com"><strong>Malcom</strong></a>, I can know for sure what my users might want to have in the next iterations.</p>

<p>All the extra functionality, even the stuff to make the app different from others,
<strong>will have to wait</strong>
. And hopefully I’ll get some feedback from the users.</p>

<p>And now, a teaser for you all.</p>

<p><img src="http://mrm.perry.es/uploads/admin/image/image/27/bikeshare-ios-sneak-peek.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>The app is In Review, hopefully in one week or two will be rockin’ on the App Store.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do more, print less]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/12/06/do-more-print-less/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-06T22:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/12/06/do-more-print-less</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve come across many people who were always saying they were learning something but never accomplished anything. Always printing new tutorials, stashing them layer after layer in their tables, but never seemed to really get past transcribing a hello world in a new language. And a lot of trees were cut because of them and their paper heaps.</p>

<p><strong>That “learning” method is wrong</strong>
.</p>

<p>You can’t learn by simply reading in our developer world. If you are learning a new design pattern, you have to implement in a real scenario. If you are learning a new language, you have to have an accomplishable goal neither easy or hard, just something in between. If you are learning a new technology, you have to put it into practice and experiment with it.</p>

<p>Theory doesn’t work for most people, your coding brain isn’t made for that. You have to learn by being proactive, by
<strong>doing things</strong>
. Copying an example doesn’t work. You can use them as a base, sure, but you can’t just copy it. You have to play with it, experiment, change, try, fail, try again, fail again, and finally get what you want working.</p>

<p>It was always this way with me: hitting a wall multiple times and then overcoming the obstacles. I can’t conceive any other way. And with all I’ve seen with the
printing tutorials a gogo guys, experience agrees with me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
