<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: computer-science | Nacho Lopez]]></title>
  <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/categories/computer-science/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-16T13:02:19+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nacho Lopez]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nacho@nlopez.io]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is your code clean?]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/03/06/is-your-code-clean/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-06T22:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/03/06/is-your-code-clean</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been reading some technical stuff lately. My latest prey has been
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Clean-Code-Handbook-Software-Craftsmanship/dp/0132350882">Clean Code</a>, by “Uncle Bob” Robert C. Martin.</p>

<p><img src="http://mrm.perry.es/uploads/admin/image/image/23/CleanCode.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>It has been very revealing about a ton of stuff and made me think a lot about what I could improve, although I don’t 100% agree with everything Bob says. I’ve also applied some of the key points to the Android coding style I recently wrote for
<a href="http://www.mobivery.com">Mobivery</a>, in the naming conventions for example.</p>

<p>Well… It’s very recommended for everyone! I wish I read it in college.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do more, print less]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/12/06/do-more-print-less/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-06T22:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/12/06/do-more-print-less</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve come across many people who were always saying they were learning something but never accomplished anything. Always printing new tutorials, stashing them layer after layer in their tables, but never seemed to really get past transcribing a hello world in a new language. And a lot of trees were cut because of them and their paper heaps.</p>

<p><strong>That “learning” method is wrong</strong>
.</p>

<p>You can’t learn by simply reading in our developer world. If you are learning a new design pattern, you have to implement in a real scenario. If you are learning a new language, you have to have an accomplishable goal neither easy or hard, just something in between. If you are learning a new technology, you have to put it into practice and experiment with it.</p>

<p>Theory doesn’t work for most people, your coding brain isn’t made for that. You have to learn by being proactive, by
<strong>doing things</strong>
. Copying an example doesn’t work. You can use them as a base, sure, but you can’t just copy it. You have to play with it, experiment, change, try, fail, try again, fail again, and finally get what you want working.</p>

<p>It was always this way with me: hitting a wall multiple times and then overcoming the obstacles. I can’t conceive any other way. And with all I’ve seen with the
printing tutorials a gogo guys, experience agrees with me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The outrageous story of the mighty CTO intern]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/11/23/the-outrageous-story-of-the-mighty-cto-intern/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T22:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/11/23/the-outrageous-story-of-the-mighty-cto-intern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Worst job offer ever.</p>

<p><img src="http://mrm.perry.es/uploads/admin/image/image/21/cto_intern.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>A
CTO offer, with that many technologies required (they ask for high skill in them)… 40h per week (8 hours/day) with a contract of 4 months being an intern. Yes, a
CTO intern. And for 600€ ($775). Unbelievable. I don’t know if cry or kill myself.</p>

<p>The worst part of it… 16 applicants.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This grinded my gears... A LOT]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/07/07/this-grinded-my-gears-a-lot/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-07T22:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/07/07/this-grinded-my-gears-a-lot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://twitter.com/_TheAway/status/221114784672776193">A friend of mine tweeted yesterday</a> about a conversation he overheard when he was having a coffee at a bar.</p>

<p>They were talking about computer specialists in general, stating that none of us is good, and
outrageously they asked for a wage over 700€/month. Seriously, I still don’t know what angered me more: the disdain or the ridiculous wage.</p>

<p>We work in a field of expertise that always asks for more and we must be learning new things always or we are useless. There are few lines of work where this happens. We go to the university and we graduate knowing that in 5/10 years tops all we learnt technology-related is completely anachronic. Of course there are exceptions
IMHO.</p>

<p>But what the f*ck were they expecting offering less than 700€? Of course, if you hire someone offering less than what an intern is worth, you can never expect to have things done!</p>

<p>That conversation was wrong in so many ways I’d better stop thinking about it and enjoy my weekend. A weekend where, of course, I’ll be learning new things.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
