<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rant | Nacho Lopez]]></title>
  <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/categories/rant/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T16:46:42+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nacho Lopez]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nacho@nlopez.io]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I don't like about working for clients]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/09/01/things-i-dont-like-about-working-for-clients/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-01T17:51:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/09/01/things-i-dont-like-about-working-for-clients</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my experience working for clients I&rsquo;ve come to realize that most of the time they don&rsquo;t want the best app they can have. Or, at least, they don’t act that way. Most of them ignore willingly the fact that you know best, that you want them to succeed because it is your passion and your job to do so, and they don&rsquo;t take your advice when they should.</p>

<p>It has been really heartbreaking to see some apps, that were meant to be awesome, to go down the drain and fail because the stubbornness of their handlers.</p>

<p>I’ve seen a client remove a perfectly valid tabbar and change it for a dashboard menu in an iOS app. Yes, in 2013. Fun fact: it happened in a published app, and the changelog in the App Store stated that it was an <em>usability improvement</em>. Nuts.</p>

<p>Trying to change the way things are done in the platform is a typical situation. Why use a picker when you could do an accordion? Why use a list when you could do a dropdown control? Why rely on the system locale settings when you can use buttons and selectors for changing the app language? I can&rsquo;t express how many times and how loud I wanted to scream <strong>an app is NOT A WEBSITE</strong>.</p>

<p>Also wanting to have the <strong>same exact behavior in Android and iOS</strong> is another instant classic. The tabbar position or the navbar layout are the most hurt in this situation. You end up with the title I&rsquo;m the middle in Android or a lot of buttons I&rsquo;m the right side on iOS. One could argue that it gives the app consistency, and that it might not feel right. <strong>You, sir, are no Facebook.</strong> Or Twitter. Or Foursquare. You are not a trendsetter. Probably <strong>the users will use a lot of other apps before they install yours.</strong> And that&rsquo;s what makes this a bad idea. Users are used to their platforms! Mr. Client, if you don&rsquo;t believe me, <a href="https://plus.google.com/114892667463719782631/posts/PXGZ48VaqHz">believe Matías Duarte</a>. I think <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matias_Duarte">he knows his stuff</a>.</p>

<p>There are also situations when a client ask you to replicate (or blatantly copy) an existent app, and the base app is fugly or has crappy usability. You then show your proposal, with the intended functionality but with a decent UX design&hellip; and gets rejected. They want to copy the crap. You insist, but it doesn&rsquo;t matter. <strong>So shit gets copied in the end</strong>, sadly for you.</p>

<p>All of these problems and absurd situations could be solved with little to none work &ndash; <strong>just be opened to suggestions!</strong> We&rsquo;re in the same boat, we want to make you a likable and usable app with gorgeous design. Let us, please! <strong>We&rsquo;d like to love working in your app!</strong></p>

<p>And, of course, there are good clients too. Not everything is black or white, there are different shades in-between. But, sadly, they are a (very welcomed) minority.</p>

<p>Anyway, working in personal side projects as an escape is pretty encouraged for avoiding the burn out. So the next post will be about <strong>a new project I&rsquo;m excited about</strong> and with lots of OSS goodness!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is fragmentation really that much of a problem in Android?]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/08/17/is-fragmentation-really-that-much-of-a-problem-in-android/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-17T17:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/08/17/is-fragmentation-really-that-much-of-a-problem-in-android</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I always read the same and never-ending articles / posts / tweets about Android&rsquo;s fragmentation. The same <a href="http://opensignal.com/reports/fragmentation.php">boring infographics</a>, the same Google Play pie charts with Android version penetration, and always the same argument about how the developers are crazy about it, like if it&rsquo;s impossible to code because of that reason. But hey, <strong>I&rsquo;m a developer, and I couldn&rsquo;t care less</strong>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not gonna say there isn&rsquo;t any fragmentation at all, it would be a huge lie. There is, of course. But through the years <strong>Android tools and framework have improved A LOT</strong>, and they embrace fragmentation. The compatibility libraries help with the interesting framework APIs. The XML resources help with layouts for different types of screens, making us to be able to code once and display the information in many different ways, or with   graphical resources, by using XML drawables.</p>

<p>It just takes a little more to get used to, coming from iOS programming for example, where everything is thought to be <em>pixel perfect</em> (though that&rsquo;s changing too, with the AutoLayout and the rumors about new types of screens in the next iPhone iterations, but still). You can&rsquo;t use hardcoded pixels to measure. You don&rsquo;t have a pretty IDE assuring that your layout is going to look perfect everywhere. You just have to take that to heart and build your interfaces avoiding things like textures and fixed sizes, in a truly responsive way.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a little harder to do it when talking about SDK support, as we know iOS versions have a lot of traction very fast. But, in my case, as <a href="http://www.mobivery.com">Mobivery</a> has the policy of supporting the two latest major versions by default, I can&rsquo;t  code at work and use the latest APIs either. So it&rsquo;s pretty much the same for me, I have to wait to use NSAttributedString in a native way too. Oh, but wait, it happens the same as in Android: there is a TTTAtributedString which does pretty much the same. Just like ActionBarSherlock or NineOldAndroids or many others I use for Android development.</p>

<p>As a little exercise left to the reader, just try to develop any universal app in iOS and the same app in Android. You will see how the actual code is pretty much the same, with the same exceptions. And now <strong>try to do it with a pure HTML5 app, and then kill yourself</strong>.</p>

<p>Each platform has its perks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android's Camera Intent killing my Application]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/04/25/android-s-camera-intent-killing-my-application/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-25T22:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/04/25/android-s-camera-intent-killing-my-application</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Working with the camera
<strong>is always a pain in the ass</strong>
. But at least in Android we have Intents. So, with little code we are able to get a working 300×300 thumbnail or even a picture with the best quality the device can offer. So I used it for a project few days ago because the project was in a hurry.</p>

<p>But things
<strong>got weird.</strong></p>

<p>The information stored in a Singleton was disappearing without a trace, and the information about sessions and current user of the app were nowhere to be found. Then a friend pointed me in the right direction, asking me to log something in the onCreate method of the current application just in case
<strong>the SO was killing the application</strong>
. And it was, indeed.</p>

<p>I had to perform some nasty tricks in the Singleton storing the session information, such as persisting some of the objects in SharedPreferences in Strings by converting them to
JSON, and the ones I couldn’t were implemented as Serializable objects and stored them in files in the application internal storage. It felt dirty and unnecessary, but had to be done. So if you can’t trust the system to persist your application memory data, I just don’t know what can you trust.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ditching Eclipse, at last]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/02/11/ditching-eclipse-at-last/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-11T22:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2013/02/11/ditching-eclipse-at-last</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m kind of
<strong>fed up with Eclipse</strong>
. I acknowledge it’s a good
IDE, but too broad and too cluttered for me.</p>

<p>So after I returned to work after my forced leave, I finally got to put in practice one of my new year resolutions: switch to
<a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/">IntelliJ
IDEA</a>. And when I finally got it to work with my maven setup it was all joy and happiness tears.</p>

<p><img src="http://mrm.perry.es/uploads/admin/image/image/22/darcula-minimized.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>And also switched my Ruby / Rails
IDE to
<a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/ruby/">RubyMine 5</a>, though I haven’t bought it yet (still on trial though).</p>

<p>But AppCode still doesn’t do it for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The outrageous story of the mighty CTO intern]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/11/23/the-outrageous-story-of-the-mighty-cto-intern/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T22:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/11/23/the-outrageous-story-of-the-mighty-cto-intern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Worst job offer ever.</p>

<p><img src="http://mrm.perry.es/uploads/admin/image/image/21/cto_intern.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>A
CTO offer, with that many technologies required (they ask for high skill in them)… 40h per week (8 hours/day) with a contract of 4 months being an intern. Yes, a
CTO intern. And for 600€ ($775). Unbelievable. I don’t know if cry or kill myself.</p>

<p>The worst part of it… 16 applicants.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
