<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: adt | Nacho Lopez]]></title>
  <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/categories/adt/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-17T17:48:44+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nacho Lopez]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nacho@nlopez.io]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I like most and what I hate most in ADT 20]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/06/29/what-i-like-most-and-what-i-hate-most-in-adt-20/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-29T22:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrmans0n.github.io/blog/2012/06/29/what-i-like-most-and-what-i-hate-most-in-adt-20</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two days ago
<a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/help/adt.html">ADT 20</a> was liberated, and I’ve been using it at work. So I thought I’d share my first impressions with you.</p>

<h3>What I love</h3>

<p>This one is easy. I love what you guys did with the layout editor. I hated down to the bone the fact I had to switch all the time between layout editor / outline / properties windows. They redesigned everything here, and now I find it a lot more usable.</p>

<p>The new logcat handling is pretty good, although I didn’t have any particular complaints about the old version.</p>

<p>One thing that made my day is the fact that you can press
<strong>cmd</strong>
 and hover over any resource, and you
finally have relevant options! Who wanted to see its definition in R.java? No- f*kin -one! You can see the string value or open the layout with the layout editor, for example. Awesome. At last.</p>

<p>Still hadn’t had the time to try the new performance viewer so I will refrain commenting about that one.</p>

<h3>What I hate</h3>

<p>Seriously, what were you thinking? At least, in the first version available (the one I’m using right now), I have to clean up my projects every time I change something at UI level. It’s annoying as hell.</p>

<p>Of course, I hate Eclipse, but that’s not new. Someday I’ll be able to code in something like Visual Studio or even better for all the platforms I really dig. In fact, that’s what really makes me want to code some Windows Phone stuff: its wonderful
IDE.</p>

<h3>Final thoughts</h3>

<p>Well, first of all, the should fix the issues asap. I don’t like Eclipse a lot so it’s like adding fuel to the fire.</p>

<p>However, each version they are improving the experience a lot. I still miss some more refactoring options, of course, but they’re going in the right direction.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
